Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - Madagascar Diaries
    - The First Malagasy, Author: Alison Jolly Diego Suarez, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      AMKB, RJ, Nat Geo, Diego Suarez, Bob Dewar, Ross McPhea, Henry Wright, Paul Verin, Jean-Aime Rakotoarisoa, Georges Heurtebise, Henry Whitehouse,
    - While Patricia walked the Boundaries Author: Alison Jolly Location: Ranomafana, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Pat Wright, patrick Daniels, Ranomafana waterfall, Ambatohaly, Namorona, Ken Creighton, Louise Emmons, David Myers, Michael Todd, Bettina Greser, Deborah Overdorf, Caroline Harcourt, Nat Geo, Patrick Daniels, Dick Byrne, Dominique Halleux, Tom Soderstrom, Philippe, Edmond, Pul Rarijaona, Ken Glander, William, Rajery, Loret, Jean Jacques Petter, Georges Randrianasolos, Peyrieras, Bernhard Meier, Roland Albignac, David Haring, RJ, KenCreighton, Ambatolahy,
    - World Bank Donor's Meeting, Author: Alison Jolly Washington, 1989; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      WB, RM, Claudine Schneider, Hans Wyss, Rajaobelina, Berndt von Droste, Bernard asquier, Francois Falloux, UNESCO, Chuck Lankester UNDP, Kenton Miller TFAP, Ken Piddington, AJ, Leif Kristofferson, Frank Schmidt, Razafindinarivo, Mark Halle, Leonard Hirsh, President Ratsiraka
    - World Bank Mission for the Environmental Action Plan Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1989; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Ber, Francis Falloux, Bruno Ribon, Vivane Ralimanga, Daniel Cremont, Jean-Roger Mercier, Oliver Langrand, Martin Nicoll, Roland Albignac, Frank Convery, Jan Post, Hans Hurni, Kuno Schaeffli, David Gibson, Lee Hannah, Donna Stauffer, Kathy Richman, Ranovenona, Biodiversity, Philippe Rajaobelina, WB, Dr. Ramahatra, RM, PAE, Jose Bronfmann, Juliette Ratsimandrava, Jean-Louis Rakotomanana, Bedo, Alaoy,
    - Bedo's Murder, Author: Alison Jolly Andasibe Bay, 1989; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Perinet, WB, Josef Andrianajaka, Frans Lanting, Georges Randrianasolo, Patricia Wright, Ranomafana, Bedo
    - Preparing for the Conables, Author: Alison Jolly Perinet, 1989; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Barber Conable, WB, Monty Yudelman, Jose Bronfmann, RJ, Levy Rakotoanison, Viviane Ralimanga, Zahamenas rainforest, Hanta Rasamimananana, Elie Rafidinarivo, Carl Jones, Wendy Strahm, Laurent Viue, WB, Richard Fife, Hubert Randrianasolo, Bedo, Bernhard Meier, Perinet, Olivier Langrand, Lucienne Wilme, Kathleen MacNamara, Leon Rajaobelina, Tom Lovejoy, RM, Ambassador Walker, Cultural Counselor Albertini, Mme Kourieh, Roland Alignac, WB,
    - Titanium Paradise, Author: Alison Jolly Saint Luce, 1989; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      deH, Ken Creighton, St. Luce, WB, Wildlife Preservation Trust, Bodo Randrianasolo, Alan Rudnik, Bill Konstant, Joan Tobias, Olivier Langrand,
    - The Conables take the Bank to the Rainforest, Author: Alison Jolly Location: Perinet, 1989; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Jose Bronfmann, WB, Barber Conable, RJ, Isaac Gomez, Paul Eisenman, Barthelemi Vaohita, Vololomihadza Rakotomanana, Joseph Andrianjaka, Dr. Paulien, Eugene Rasolonirina, Bedo, Eugenie Bedo, Guy Razafindralambo, Vivienne Ralimanga, Maxine Zafera, Victorien Rakoto, Martin Nicoll, Prof. L.T. Wassertal, Charles Darwin, Minister Zafera, Jon Pollock, MGB, AHKB, Jean-Louis Rakotomanana,
    - Demonstration in pink sisal sunhats Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1991; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      RJ, Cesaire Rabenoro, Henri Roger, Guy Razanamazy, Howard Walker, Monique Rodriguez, Monja Jaona, Ratsiraka, Monique Traoure, Unicef,
    - Waiting for Tourists, Author: Alison Jolly Fort Dauphin, 1991; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      RJ, Ber, Unicef, WWF, Alison Richard,
    - Famine in the South, Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1991; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      deH, Aline de heaulme, John Davidson, CJ Rushin-Bell, Lisa Gaylord, Bob Freitas, Unicef, David Fletcher, World Food Program, AJ,
    - Letter to Richard on the famine Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1992; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      RJ, MJ, Roger Botrala, Unicef, WFP, Monique Andreas, Vivienne Rakoto,
    - The PAZ-SUD meeting Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1992; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Matthias Guenou, Muriel Glasgow, Roland Ramahatra, Horace Gatien, Helen Crowley, Yves de Rousson, Unicef, Ratsimamanga, General Soja,
    - The Lemur War, Author: Alison Jolly Berenty and New York, Sept 1992-Jan 1993; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Monsieur Rakotomalala, Lucille Allorge, Laura Hood, Bob Sussman, Michelle Sauther, Michael Pereira, Gwendolyn Wood, Ber, Sharon Katz, deH, Helen Crowley, Rekanoky, Hilary Simons,
    - The Village of the Fig Tree, Author: Alison Jolly Ranomafana, 1993; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Lord Ravanomasina, Bob Brandstetter, Jean-Marc Andriamanantena, Mpanjaka Zafy, Zanaka, Ravanomasina, Lesonina, Raymond, Ambodiaviavy, Rahasoa, Jamie spencer, Paul Hanson,
    - Can Development love Conservation Author: Alison Jolly Location: Ranomafana, 1993; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Bernhard Meier, Patricia Wright, Dennis, Jean-Marc Andriamanantena, Bob Brandstetter, Emile Rajeriarson, Rasabo, Loret, Donald Stone, Dai Peters, Joe Peters, Dan Turk, USAID, Ranomafana, Roy Hagin, madame Pauline, Ratsirarson,
    - The GEF Priorities Workshop Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1995; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      RM, Olivier langrand, Sylvere Rakotofiringa, Paul oiselle, AMJ, RJ, Frans Lanting, Rachel Rabesandratana, Quentin Bloxham, Martin Nicoll, Chris Raxworthy, Mme Berthe, Joseph Andriamampianina, Roland Albignac,
    - The World comes to Ranomafana Author: Alison Jolly, 1998; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      RJ, Ernesto Rodriguez, Jatna Supriatna, SAJ, Dr. Li, Dr Zhang, John MacKinnon, Sukey Zeeve, Patricia Wright, Prof. Toshisada Nishida, Loret, Mme Rakotosamimanana, Pablo Stevenson, Ed Lewis, Norman Uphoff, Jocelyn Rakotomalala,
    - Madame Berthe was Dancing Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1998; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Madame Berthe, Same Wasser, GERP, RJ, Hilary Box, Kaberi Kar Gupta, Leticia Dominguez Brandao, Hanta Rasamimanana, Lisa gould, Mukesh Chalise, Adrian Warren, Jan Jekeilek, Marcel Hladik, Joelisoa Ratsirarson, lsion richard, Andy whiten, Sally Boysen, Joseph Andrianampianina, Elwyn simons, Prithajit Singh, Yves Rumpler, JeaJacques Petter, Dorothy Fragaszy
    - Original diary/letters from Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1962-63; diary/letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Tana, Perinet, Ampijoroa, Nosy Be, Fort Dauphin, Berenty
    - Camping at Anja Mandrare overflight Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 2004; Drawing, typed notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Fort dauphin, Ber, Antananarivo
    - Round Madagascar Cruise with Peter Scott and Cabots and Daphne Shih Author: Alison Jolly, AMK, 1986; Letters (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Tom Cabot, Peter Scott, AMK, AJ,
    - Conservation by the aliens Author: Alison Jolly New York, 1986; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Mayor Dinkins
    - Round Madagasgar Cruise Whale Sanctuary Indian ocean Salvage Lyall Watson Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1986; Handwritten and typed notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Lyall Watson, Joseph Randrianasolo, WB, Julie Edstrom,
    - Recommendations and Summary of Alison Jolly education volet proposals for PAE Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1989; Yyped notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Claude George
    - Letter to Laura Coolidge - an exceptional Princeton student who died in childbirth Author: Alison Jolly Antananarivo, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Laura Coolidge, AJ, WWF, RM, SAJ
    - Simon Peer's eyewitness account of Ratsikara massacre Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 1991; Handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Simon Peer
    - Antananarivo Author: Alison Jolly, 1991; Letter (Box 1, Folder 5)
      RJ, AJ, Forces Vives
    - Antananarivo Author: Alison Jolly, 1991; Letter (Box 1, Folder 5)
      RJ, Beatrice Gakuba, Michelle Ramahatra, Alison Jolly
    - Drought, Earthwatch Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1992; Typed notes, photocopied article (Box 1, Folder 6)
      deH, Hanta Rasamimnana, 'Harsh Lessons in the art of Survival' Focus Vol 1:94-98,
    - UNICEF and World women's Congress Author: Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1992; Handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Ramahatra, Rabary, Vivianne Ralimanga, Muriel Glasgow
    - Shooting of Reptile Smugglers Author: Don reid Location: Ampijoroa tortoise Breeding Centre, 1993; Typed notes, fax (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Don Reid, Jersey Wildlife Preservation Trust
    - The Queen's Palace Burns Author: Patrick Location: Antananarivo, 1995; Typed letter (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - CAMP analysis Author: Alison Jolly Paris, New York City, 1995; Letter (Box 1, Folder 6)
      RM, Mme Berthe, Joseph Anriamampianina, RJ,
    - Interview with President Ratsiraka Author: Alison Jolly Location: Washington, 1997; Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Pat Wright, Leon Rajobelina
    - Maroantsetra Author: AJ Nosy Mangabe, 1999; Letter, copied handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Tour with Nat Geog Committee for Exploration Author: Alison Jolly Location: Durban, Madagascar, Handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
      AMJ, RJ, Pat Wright,
    - Berenty field notes, Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Busload of tourists
    - Notebook: Duke of Edinburgh's Speech. Morondava with Kathleen Macnamara, Amoco Rig in Tsangy, Swiss Forestry Kirindy and Analabe Author: Alison Jolly Location: Tsingy, Kirindy and Analabe, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Duke of Edinburgh, RJ, AJ, Luc Hoffman, RM, Tiandraza, Randriansolo, Ramarozaka,
    - Draft Introduction to "The Mad. Diaries Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Draft for Introduction to "The Mad Diaries" Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Madagascar Conference Author: Alison Jolly, 1970; Notes and letters (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Conference pour le Protection de la Nature Tananarive, Nature Malgache, Heritage Mondiale, letters from Jean-Jacques Petter, Monique Pariente
    - Patricia Wright Location: Madagascar, 1990s; Notes, letters and report (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Ranomafana National Park Project evaluation
  - National Geographic Travels
    - Tulear Author: Alison Jolly, 1985; Notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maroantsetra Author: Alison Jolly, 1985; Notebook (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maroantsetra Author: Alison Jolly, 1985; Letter (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Jose Tanaka Author: Alison Jolly Maroantsetra, 1985; Notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maroansetra, Masoala Author: Alison Jolly Location: Maroantsetra, Masoala, 1985; Notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - David edelman Author: Alison Jolly, Diego Suarez, 1987; Notes (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ordre Nationale, Author: Babenoro Antananarivo, 1985; Letter typed (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - IAGS Author: Lee Durrell Madagascar, 1985; Notes typed (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Jersey Widlife Preservation Trust
    - Julie the Chimpanzee, Death of children Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Archaeology Colloquim Diego Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Aye aye expedition Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Paris Aye-ayes, Eleanor and the Aye-Ayes Author: Alison Jolly Location: Paris, Mananara, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Nat Geog notes on Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Documents
    - Napoleon at St Catherines Author: Alison Jolly, 1987; 2 notebooks (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - St Catherine's 11 Location: St Catherine's Island, 1987; Two photographs (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - World Bank - WWF Washington meeting Location: Washington, 1989; Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - World Bank in Washington Author: Alison Jolly, 1989; Notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Workshop on Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly New York, 1989; Typed and handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - World Bank Donor's Meeting Author: Alison Jolly Washington, 1989; Letter (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Diary Conables and St Luce 1989 Author: Alison Jolly Location: Perinet, St. Luce, 1989; Notebook (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - To Quammen for "The Song of the Dodo" Author: Alison Jolly Location: Perinet, 1989; Letter and notes (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Pink Sunhats, Author: AJ Antananarivo, 1991; Letter (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Drought Diary notes Author: Alison Jolly, 1991; Notes (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letter on Southern Famine Author: Alison Jolly, 1992; Letter (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Village of the Fig Tree, Author: Alison Jolly Ranomafana, 1993; Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Ranomafana evaluation uncut and unexpurgated Author: Alison Jolly Location: Ranomafana, 1993; Notebook (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Translation of the de Heaulme Berenty comic book, "La Terre des Milles Reproches Location: Berenty, early 1990's; Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - China Author: AJ China, 1986; Notebook (Box 1, Folder 17)
      travels with SAJ, Beijing, Wuhan, Tibet
    - China Diary Author: Alison Jolly China, 1986; Typed manuscript diary (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Wuhan, Beijing, Kumming, Xishuanbanna, Chengdu, Lhasa,
    - Story Author: Alison Jolly, 1986; Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Aliens conserve New York
    - Story dream Author: Alison Jolly, 1986; Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Nat. Geog. Covers Burgess Shale
    - On Madagascar, Friends and Lemurs Author: Henry Mitchell, 1987; Photocopied news article (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Tom Lovejoy
    - Phaeton Author: MJB, 1987; Poem (Box 1, Folder 19)
      MJB
    - Cuba diary typed notes Author: Alison Jolly, 1997; Typed diary notes (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mary LaTrob Bateman, 1999; Gallery card (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Morris Bishop Fund donation Author: Alison Jolly, 1999; Fax (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Wedding poem by Morris Bishop, at Richard and Nora's wedding Author: MJB Location: Hovw, 1963; poem (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Trip to Rajasthan, Author: Alison Jolly India, 1999; Notes and card (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - ISA poem, Poem (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - What really happened in Rio? By Jolly, June 16, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Environment and Development Conference Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1992; Notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - World's Women Congress Location: Beijing, 1991; Notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Tom Lovejoy Author: AJ, June; Letter (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Conference notes Author: Alison Jolly, 1992; Notebook (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Conference notes Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Family letter Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Letter to Dickon on conference Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Field visit to Amazonian project Location: Belem, Brazil, 1992; Notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Family letter on Rio Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Belem, Brazil notes Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Rio and the Future lecture Author: S. Ramphal Location: Rio, Brazil, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Family letter Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - UN Conference staff pass, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Toronto Star article Author: Michele Landsberg, 1991; Newspaper article, photocopied (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - The Cottage, Ithaca Author: Alison Jolly, Typed notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - AAAS fellowship Location: Princeton, 1993; Certificate and letter (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Silly Thriller set on Nosy Managabe Author: Alison Jolly Location: Masoala, 1993; Notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nightmare Author: Alison Jolly, 1993; Notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - New Iberia, Chimpanzee Lab., Author: Alison Jolly Louisiana: New Iberia, 1994; Notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
      BBC Monkey in the Mirror
    - Invitation to book launch, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Lucy's Legacy
    - Zaire diary Author: Alison Jolly, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      BBC Monkey in the Mirror, Bonobos, Karen Bass, Evelyn Ono Vineberg, Martin Saunders, A Week in Zaire
    - Visit to Koko Author: Alison Jolly San Francisco, 199? (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Gorilla Location: San Francisco, 1989; journal (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Koko
    - Susie's Papers Author: SAJ, 1990-2000; papers (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Queering Development, Gendered Art of writing a woman's life, tongzhi responses to lesbian/gay identity
    - Professional letters A-B, up to 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Academie Malgache, Ordre National de Madagascar, Roland Albignac, Allorge, Josephine Andrews, Jocelyn Alexander, Rauf Ali, Donald allen, WWF, Myrdene Anderson, Rabodo Andriantiferana, Apenheul Zoo, David Attenborough, Molly Badham Twyecross Zoo, Janice and John Baldwin, Kim Bard, J. Bell British Invasion of Mad. 1942, Irwin Bernstein, Mireille Bertrand, Joseph Birdsell, Charles Blanc, Liz and Tony Bomford, Francois Bouriere, Geoffrey Bourne, G.K. Brain, David Burney, Jerome Bruner, Norman Budnitz, Kathryn Dairis Blumenthal-jones, Connie Brandtsteller, Thomas Bass
    - Professional letters C-F, up to 2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Coimbra-Filho, Phil Chapman, Chevalier-Skolnikoff, David Chivers, D.J Chivers, Chepko-Sade, Anne B. Clark, Preston Cloud, T.H. Clutton-Brock, Dewsbury, Bryony Coombe, Ursula Cowgill, Helena Curtis, A.W.Clausen, Daniel Dennett, Irven DeVore, Gerald Durrell, Lee Durrell, Thomas Eisner, Irenaus Eibl-Eibesfeldt, John F. Eisenberg, Annette Erhlich, Roger Fouts, George Macdonald Fraser, H.H. Coolidge
    - Professional letters G-H, up to 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Madhav Gadgil, Birute Galdikas, R. Allen Gardner, Steve Gartlan, V. Geist, Kathleen R. Gibson, Jane Goodall, Gombe stream research Centre, Jacqueline Goodenow, Steve Goodman, Edward Gould, Bettina Grieser Johns, D.R. Griffin, E.O Guerrant, Arnaud de Guitaut, Donna Haraway, Caryl P. Haskins, Mark Auser, Hosking, Sarah Blaffer Hrdy, Alan D. Hutchison, K. R. Hobbs,
    - Professional letters J-K, up to 2000 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Carl Jones, E.J. Kahn, William Katz, Michael Kavanagh, Timothy Keith-Jones, Kelowna Museum, K.A.R. kennedy, Kew, Keynes, Keys, Kinnaird and O'Brian, Kingdon, Jermy, Janzen, Klopfer, H.A. Krebs
    - Professional letters L, up to 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Landsberg, Larson, la Bastille, Lancaster, Landry, R.M laws, Leakey, Lavelle, Lees, Egbert Leigh, Lincoln Zoo, Louisville Zoo, Leighton, E.Linden, Tom Lovejoy, P.P. Lowry,
    - Professional letters M, up to 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Dorcas MacClintock, B.J. Mack, K. MacKinnon, Lee McGeorge, Joe Macedonia, John Maynard Smith, Betty J. Meggers, H.A.H. Melville, Anne Mertl-Millhollen, Charles G. Messing, Stephen Miller, S.M Mohnot, Ashley Montagu, Norman Moore, janet Moore, Dervla Murphy,
    - Professional letters N-O, up to 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      John Napier, Prudence Napier, L.T. Nash, Michael Nathan, Stephen Nash, Nishida, New York Zoological Society, Phillip Ndegwa, Carsten Niemitz, Robert Oakeshott, Philippe Oberle, Sheila O'Connor, John Oates, Perez Olindo, P.J. Olney, William L.R. Oliver
    - Professional letters P-R, up to 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Morton D. Paley, J. Pollack, Hugh L. Popenoe, Joyce Powzyk, David Premack, Holger Preuschoft, Barbara Pryes-Williams, David Quammen, Caroline M. Pond, George Rabb, Rachel Rabesandratana, Liliane Rakotomalala, Razafindramany, Katherine Ralls, Beberonn Randriamampiononz, Randriamanantenina, Georges Randrianasolo, Hanta Rasamimanana, Peter Raven, Marquise Revelle, Sandy Richards, M. Ridley, Arthur J. Riopelle, Dillon Ripley, Mary Ripley, P.A. Rizzo, Joan Robinson, Hugh Rowell, Thelma Rowell, Hallie Robbins, Burton Raffel, G. Ramanantsoa
    - Professional letters S-Z, up to 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      R.V. Short, M.J. Strong, R.E. Vaughan, Pierre Verin, Alex Walter, Barbara Ward, Renee Winn, Whitten, WWF Tom Lovejoy
    - Alison Richard, Bob Dewar Location: Yale, Cambridge, Beza mahafaly, letters (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - John Buettner-Janusch Location: Yale, Duke, 1980s-90s; Letters and newspaper cuttings (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Evelyn Hutchinson Location: Yale, 1970-91; letters and newspaper cuttings (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Charles Remington, Peabody Museum, Yale, Hutchinson Fund, Hutchinson Collection, Memorial luncheon notes
    - Nabokov Location: Ithaca, 1990s; letters about Nabokov book, reviews, articles and newspaper cuttings (Box 2, Folder 9)
      revised 'I think I have been here before', Nabokov's Butterflies, Galya Diment, Nabokov Studies, Morris Bishop,
    - Stephen Nash original art for Lucy's Legacy Location: Princeton, 2003; drawings and printed e-mail (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Lucy's Legacy reviews and notices Location: Princeton, 2000; newspaper cuttings and photocopies (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Reviews and Notices Location: Berenty, 1970s-2000s; newspaper cuttings and photocopies (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Lords and Lemurs, Evolution of Primate Behaviour, Anne La Bastille, Eight Women in the Wild, Intl Wildlife, A World like our own, Philip Morrison, Ian Tattersall, Patrick Marnham, Play, Lemur Behaviour, Robert Hinde, John Eisenberg, Francois Bouliere, Jean Jacques Petter, John Buettner Janusch, Alan Walker, H. Hediger, Patrick Bateson, Holger Preuschoft, Evolutionary and Genetic Biology of Primates,
    - Copy of "The Evolution of Primate Behavior" with notes and highlights (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Television Location: Berenty, letters, notes, memos, contracts (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Animal Planet, Lemur kingdom, BBC, Monkey in the Mirror, Tropical Time Machine, CBC, CINETEVE Nabokov film, Marathon Berenty, National Public Radio, Survival Anglia, Das Tieer Top Productions, Visty Productions, Koko the Gorilla, Adrian Warren, Partidge films, Dance of the Sifaka, A Lemur's Tale, Andy Young, Archipelago films, Living Edens,
    - "Fiches zoologiques" Location: Antananarivo Madagascar, 1960s-70s; letters (Box 2, Folder 15)
      successful provision of "Fiches zoologiques" for Malagasy schools, P. Roederer ORSTOM
    - Andrianampianina booklet Location: Madagascar, 1979; letters (Box 2, Folder 15)
      effort to translate Andrianampianina booklet
    - IDRC Location: Canada, 1978-9; letters and report (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Frank remarks from LG Lessard, IDRC Canada and David W Steadman, Rafael RABE proposal of priorities
    - Savoka Project Location: Madagascar Rainforest, 1979; letter and project document (Box 2, Folder 15)
      R Langley
    - Faith McNulty Location: Madagascar, 1975; letter (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - A World Like our Own and Madagascar Key Environment Location: Madagascar, 1971-78; letters (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Roger Ramanantoanison, Etienne Rakotomaria, Guy and Lily Ramanantsoa, Lalao Rakotomalala, Madagascar key environment, David Whaley, Albert Maxim, Rafael Rabe, Cesaire Rabenoro, Joelina Ratsirarson, Henri Roger, Folo Emmanuel, Jean de Heaulme, Henry de Heaulme, Joseph Andrianampianina
    - Determinaton du statut de l'aigle autour de Madagascar Author: Bernd-Ulrich Location: Madagascar, 1979; project report (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Madagascar acts to save wildlife Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1970s; article (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Madagascar Location: Madagascar, 1978; newspaper articles (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Education in the Malagasy Republic Author: Richard and Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1976; report (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Education and structural adjustment in Madagascar
    - Survival of the Angonoka Author: jonah A. Andrianarivo Location: Ampijoroa, 1977; summary report (Box 2, Folder 15)